A murdered wife. A one-armed man. An obsessed detective. The chase begins.
The Fugitive is a action, thriller, drama film directed by Andrew Davis.
Wrongfully convicted of murdering his wife and sentenced to death, Richard Kimble escapes
from the law in an attempt to find the real killer and clear his name.
Richard Kimble, played by Harrison Ford.
Samuel Gerard, played by Tommy Lee Jones.
Cosmo Renfro, played by Joe Pantoliano.
Charles Nichols, played by Jeroen Krabbé.
Biggs, played by Daniel Roebuck.
Poole, played by L. Scott Caldwell.
The Fugitive is a 1993 American action thriller film, directed by Andrew Davis, with a script
co-written by Jeb Stuart and David Twohy, from a previous story draft which Twohy had written.
Based on the 1960s TV series, itself loosely inspired by the trial of Sam Sheppard, the film stars
Harrison Ford, Tommy Lee Jones, Sela Ward, Joe Pantoliano, Andreas Katsulas, and Jeroen Krabbé.
After being framed for the murder of his wife and
sentenced to death, vascular surgeon Dr.
Richard Kimble (Ford) escapes from custody following a bus crash.
Kimble sets out to find the real killer and clear his name,
while being hunted by the police and a team of U.S.
marshals, led by Deputy Samuel Gerard (Jones).
The Fugitive premiered in Westwood, California, on July 29, 1993, and
was released in the United States on August 6, 1993.
It was a critical and commercial success, spending six weeks as the number-one film in the United
States, and grossing nearly $370 million worldwide against a $44 million budget.
It was the third-highest-grossing film of 1993 worldwide, with an
estimated 44 million tickets sold in the United States.
It was nominated for seven Academy Awards, including Best
Picture; Tommy Lee Jones won for Best Supporting Actor.
It was followed by the 1998 film U.S.
Marshals, in which Jones reprised his role as Deputy Marshal Sam
Gerard, along with some others of his earlier marshals team.
The film explores themes of chicago, illinois,
escape, chase, doomed man, surgeon.
The tone is emotional and intense.